<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Academic</title>
    <link>https://alyona-v.github.io/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://alyona-v.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://alyona-v.github.io/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://alyona-v.github.io/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Individual Project</title>
      <link>https://alyona-v.github.io/project/indproject/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alyona-v.github.io/project/indproject/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week I did lab work on three subjects. According to the Computer Workshop on Information Technology, this was a PWM lab, it was performed using an Arduino. The concept of PWM was analyzed using the example of controlling the brightness of an LED using two buttons. Laboratory work on programming technologies was devoted to the concept of classes in the C ++ language, on operating systems the emacs text editor and programming in the UNIX OS command processor, batch files were analyzed. More about the command processor:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A command processor (command shell, shell command interpreter) is a program that allows the user to interact with the operating system.
computer. In operating systems such as UNIX / Linux, the most commonly used
the following shell implementations:
Bourne shell (sh) is a standard UNIX/Linux command shell,
containing a basic, but at the same time a complete set of functions;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;– C-shell (or csh)—a Bourne shell add-on that uses a C-like
command syntax with the ability to save the history of command execution;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;– the Korn shell (or ksh)—resembles the C shell, but the program control statements are compatible with those of the Bourne shell;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BASH - short for Bourne Again Shell (Bourne shell again), basically combines the properties of C and Korn shells (developed by the Free Software Foundation).
POSIX (Portable Operating System Interface for Computer Environments)—a set of standards
descriptions of interfaces for interaction between the operating system and application programs.
The POSIX standards were developed by the IEEE (Institute of Electrical and Electronics
Engineers) to ensure compatibility between different UNIX/Linux-like operating systems and portability of application programs at the source code level.
POSIX-compliant shells are based on the Korn shell.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
